Homework 3 – CareerTrak and Career Fair

Name: Jessica Hoffman

Course: CIS150-77 Date: 3/27/2016

JESSICA HOFFMAN

Louisville, KY | 224-558-2434 (mobile) | jhhoff02@cardmail.louisville.edu

OBJECTIVE

As an undergraduate student at the College of Business at the University of Louisville, I am currently pursuing a bachelor's degree in CIS (Computer Information Systems). My past job experiences primarily involved interacting with customers and coding applications for the .Net/Mobile team at LG&E Center. In addition to years of customer service experience, I have utilized computers in multiple jobs and academic settings. Presently, I am interested in finding a CIS-related part-time, co-op, or internship opportunity to build my skills and CIS experience.

COMPUTER SKILLS

Java – 1 semester of experience creating Java classes and programs

C# - 1 semester of experience building classes in Visual Studio

HTML5 and CSS - 2 years of experience practicing HTML5 and CSS JavaScript, TypeScript, AngularJS 2.0 - 1 semester of experience

Software

- · Excel Intermediate experience using Excel (functions, cell references, interactive worksheets)
- · MS Office Expert experience using all other Microsoft Office programs such as MS Word, Paint, PowerPoint, OneDrive, Outlook, Lync
- · MS Visual Studio Intermediate experience using VS to build mobile applications
- · WallabyJS Intermediate experience using Wallaby to unit-test applications
- · Skype, WebEx, Jabber, Lync for internal business communications

Operating Systems

- · Windows 10 years of experience, very familiar with Windows XP, Windows Vista, Windows 7, Windows 8 (and 8.1)
- · Linux 2 years of experience using Linux Mint distro on a personal PC

Other

- · Between 75-90 average wpm typing best speed: 121 on play.typeracer.com
- · Agile 1 semester experience using Agile techniques to develop apps in a team

JOB EXPERIENCE

2013-2015 Employee of Dairy Queen, Round Lake Beach, IL

- Primarily customer service (ensuring customer satisfaction, resolving issues, promoting positivity, handling receipts and cash using a register, preparing desserts and meals)
- · Assisted the manager in training/supervising/advising new employees 2014-2015
- · Ran errands for manager

2014-2015 Work-study employee, University of Massachusetts Astronomy Dept., Amherst, MA

- Worked in an office setting using computers to communicate with faculty, archive information for the Astronomy Department
- · Helped plan and set up for Astronomy Dept. colloquiums

2015 Work-study employee receptionist, University of Louisville Arts and Sciences Advising Office, Louisville, KY

> · Worked in an office setting at the receptionist desk, assisting students in making academic advising appointments to see their advisors and resolving small issues that don't require advisors

· Daily use of GradesFirst program, Lync for communication with advisors and co-workers, and phones

2016-Present LG&E IT Intern for .Net/Mobile Team, LG&E Center, Louisville, KY

· Currently work in an office setting developing corporate applications in a team.

· Daily use of Agile: meet with end users every day to discuss app progress. Meet every other week to demo the app so far

· Daily use of Angular 2.0, SQL, C#, TypeScript, and Jabber.

EDUCATION

2015-Present Currently attending University of Louisville (Expected Graduation: May 2018), Louisville, KY

2014-2015 Attended University of Massachusetts, Amherst, MA

2010-2015 Attended and graduated from Round Lake Senior High School, Round Lake Beach, IL

OTHER SKILLS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Calculus Earned a 5 on the AP Calculus test

English Earned a 4 on the AP English Language and Composition test and a 4 on the AP English Literature and Composition

test

Earned a 30 on the ACT twice ACT

GPA Earned 4.0+ in HS, 3.8 first semester at UMass, and 3.7+ current U of L GPA

Illinois State Scholar

Earned this title resulting from ACT and GPA in HS

Earned position of flute section leader in HS Concert Band after 8+ years of playing Section Leader

Center for Conservation Leadership Program

Accepted into CCL centered in Lake Forest, IL, and participated in the 2 year program involving volunteer work and stewardship projects

Accounting 1 semester experience mastering basic principles of accounting and GAAP

Statistics 1 semester experience working with data, probabilities, ANOVA, and regression analysis



job postings

Application Developer

United Parcel Service of America, Inc. (UPS)

Posted: Mar 21, 2016

POSITION TYPE Full-Time YEARS OF EXPERIENCE All NUMBER OF OPENINGS

CAREER SALARY POSTING DATE

DIVISION

Entry Level TBD

March 21, 2016

EXPIRATION DATE April 21, 2016

DESCRIPTION

ACTUAL JOB LOCATION

Are you looking to launch your Information Technology career? If so, then UPS is the place for you!

UPS is now recognized as a technology company spending more than \$1 billion a year on information technology. UPS provides its customers unparalleled capability in tracking and distribution intelligence. This technological infrastructure also enables UPS to provide fully integrated Web-enabled, business-to-business solutions.

UPS Information Services, a leader in information technology, is currently seeking career-minded individuals

to join our team. If you are highly motivated with a degree in Computer Science or related discipline, then UPS is a great place for you to advance your career. Job Description:

The Applications Developer performs duties and tasks to support full systems life cycle management (e.g., analyses, technical requirements, design, coding, testing, implementation of systems and applications software, etc.). He/She

JOB MATCH: 78.05%

HOW TO APPLY

Apply online at https://www.jobsups.com/job/louisville/applicationsdeveloper/1187/1634146

IMPORTANT DATES

Posted On:

March 21, 2016

Applications Accepted Until:

April 21, 2016

SCREENING CRITERIA

All CIS Programs



software by symplicity™

I attended the CIS/CECS Career Fair on March 9th held at the University Club building on campus. If these are unreadable I would be happy to show you the materials in person.

